Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth papers, Inclusive: 1826-1965, undated, Bulk: 1930-1943
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth papers
Inclusive: 1826-1965, undated, Bulk: 1930-1943
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
43
Aynesworth, Dr. Kenneth Hazen, 1873 - 1944
31 document boxes and 3 oversized boxes.
The Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth papers consist of family materials, correspondence, literary productions, collected materials, and medical records collected by Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth, a local doctor who gave the first donation to The Texas Collection in 1923.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
Dr. Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth was a prominent surgeon in the Waco community during the early 1900s and a famous collector of Texan materials. The gift of his personal library and papers began what is now The Texas Collection.
Kenneth Aynesworth, the son of George Levin and Ellen Hickman Aynesworth, was born in Florence, Texas, on 1873 February 9. He attended Baylor University from 1892 to 1894,and was once a roommate of Pat Neff. In 1899, Aynesworth earned his medical degree from the University of Texas Medical School at Galveston. Three years later, on 1902 December 31, he married Maude Brian. The couple had four children: Kenneth, Jr., Edna Maude, Nancy, and Brian.
His work in the field of medicine brought many opportunities to Aynesworth. While finishing his doctoral degree, he interned at John Sealy Hospital in Galveston. In 1902, prior to his marriage to Maude Brian, Aynesworth pursued postgraduate studies at the Friedrich Wilhelm University in Berlin. Returning to the United States, Aynesworth began his own private practice of general surgery in Waco, Texas. In 1909, he studied at the prestigious medical school at John Hopkins University. For over forty years, Dr. Aynesworth practiced medicine in the Waco area, primarily at Providence Hospital. Many of his medical research papers can be found in the collection. Despite his busy work schedule, Aynesworth was involved in a number of medical and local organizations including the Waco Board of Health, the Waco School Board, the Waco Planning and Zoning Commission, and the American College of Surgeons.
In addition to his professional work, Dr. Aynesworth was a collector of Texas history. In 1923, he donated hundreds of items to Baylor University in order to found The Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth Texas History Collection. To ensure the collection was properly funded, Aynesworth contributed to the institution on an annual basis. The name of the repository was changed to the Texas Historical Collection, which later became The Texas Collection.
Aynesworth devoted much of his spare time promoting the education of others. He donated a large collection of American Indian archaeological materials to the John K. Strecker Museum, now known as the Mayborn. For his generosity, Baylor University awarded Dr. Aynesworth with an honorary law degree in 1933. In the late 1930s, Aynesworth served as a regent for the University of Texas, where a small collection of his papers are housed to this day. On 1944 October 30, Aynesworth died of a cerebral hemorrhage. He is buried in Oakwood Cemetery.
Scope and Content
The Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth papers range in chronology from 1826 to 1965, with the bulk of the materials dated from 1930 to 1943. The largest series in the collection are Series I. Family and Series II. Correspondence. Dr. Aynesworth maintained a steady correspondence with nuclear and extended families as well as his friends and co-workers. Series VII. Literary Productions also contains a significant number of medical essays written by Dr. Aynesworth.
Arrangement
The Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth papers were fairly well-organized prior to this latest level of processing. A detailed folder inventory and brief biographical sketch already existed. However, some of the clippings were deteriorating and the folders were over-stuffed. The current arrangement reflects the original order of the collection, but folder titles have been changed occasionally.
The Kenneth Hazen Aynesworth Papers now consists of eight series: I. Family, II. Correspondence, III. Photographic Materials, IV. Medical Practice, V. Subject Files, VI. Collected Materials, VII. Literary Productions, and VIII. Personal.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 43. Acquired 1923-00-00
Related Resources
Related references
"Baylor Mourns Death of K.H. Aynesworth." The Baylor Lariat. 1944 November 3.
Kelley, Dayton, ed. The Handbook of Waco and McLennan County, Texas. Waco: Texian Press, 1972.
“The Texas Collection Turns 85.” Accessed 2013 January 29.
Wygant, Larry J. “Aynesworth, Kenneth Hazen.” Handbook of Texas Online. Accessed 2013 January 29.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Aynesworth, K. H. (Kenneth Hazen)
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- Alumni and alumnae.
Places
McLennan County (Tex.) -- History.; Texas -- History.; Waco (Tex.) -- History.
Subjects
Genealogy.; Physicians -- Texas.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Essays.; Legal documents.; Manuscripts.; Pamphlets.; Periodicals.; Photographs.; Speeches.
- Family, 1826-1965, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  The family series contains correspondence, genealogical materials, and general documents pertaining to Dr. Kenneth Aynesworth and his family. Subseries I. Family Correspondence is one of the largest sections in the Aynesworth Papers. The materials are in average to good condition.
  - Correspondence, 1895-1945, undated; 1; This subseries contains eight document boxes.
    This subseries contains correspondence that Kenneth Aynesworth exchanged between himself and his family members including his wife (Maude Brian), his children (Kenneth, Edna, Brian) and other relatives. The materials are in average to good condition.
    Arrangement
    The folders are organized alphabetically by the name of the family member to whom Kenneth was writing.
    - General, 1923 April 9-12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General, 1923 April 17-1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - General, 1933 March-1934 October (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - General, 1934 December-1935 May (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - General, 1935 June-1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - General, 1938-1940 April (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - General, 1940 June-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - General, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - General, 1944-1945, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Annie Aynesworth, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1931-1932 January (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1932 February-April (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1932 May-1933 May (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1933 June-December (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1935 January-May (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1935 July-October (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1935 November-1936 April (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1936 May-August 26 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1936 August 27-1937 February (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1937 March-April (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1937 May-July 8 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1937 July 11-August 20 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1937 August 23-October 19 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1937 October 26-December 6 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1937 December 8-1938 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1938 January 28-March 13 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1938 March 28-May 5 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1938 May 12-June 14 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Family: Correspondence: Brian Aynesworth, 1938 June 25-1943 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1943 June 27-August 20 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1943 August 20-October 2 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1943 October 8-November 5 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1943 November 5-29 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1943 December 4-25 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1944, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Dan Aynesworth, 1934-1942 August (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Dan Aynesworth, 1942 November-1945, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Edna Aynesworth, 1929-1938 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Edward Aynesworth, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Ellen Aynesworth, 1896-1898 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Ellen Aynesworth, 1902-1906 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - George Levin Aynesworth, 1932 March 8-1933 May 26 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - George Levin Aynesworth, 1933 November 30-1936 December 3 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - George Levin Aynesworth, 1937 March 24-July 19 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - George Levin Aynesworth, 1937 November 20-1939 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - George Levin Aynesworth, 1939 April 18-1941 July 16 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - George Levin Aynesworth, 1941 July 21-1942 May 20, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Hiram Aynesworth, 1940 August 8 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Hiram Aynesworth, 1940 August 14-September 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Horace Aynesworth, 1901-1902 May (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Horace Aynesworth, 1902 September-1934, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Isaiah Aynesworth, 1902-1903 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1912-1932 March (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1932 August-1933 April 18 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1933 April 28 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1933 April 29-May 25 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1933 May 27 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1933 September-November (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1934 May-September 11 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1934 September 11-25 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1934 September 26-October (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1934 November-1935 January 20 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1935 January 24-1936 February 25 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1936 February 28-March 10 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1936 March 23-May 5 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1936 May 6-September 9 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1936 September 26-1937 January 20 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1937 January 27-April (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1937 July-August 21 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1937 August 23-September 11 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1937 September 11-23 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1937 October-1938 April 8 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1938 April 12-August 20 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1938 August 26-December (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1939 January-October 18 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1939 October 23-December (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1940 January-April (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1940 May-July, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1930 January-July 12 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1930 July 28-1931 March (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1931 April-1932 April (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1932 May-1933 February 7 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1933 February 8-October (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1933 November-1934 February (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1934 April-August (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1934 September-1935 July (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1935 August-1936 March (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1936 April-1939 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1942 June-July (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1942 August-September (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1942 October-1943 January (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1943 February-April (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1943 May-July (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1943 August (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1943 September-November 7 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1943 November 22-December (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Kenneth Aynesworth, Jr., 1944, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Mary Alice Aynesworth, 1934-1942 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Mary Alice Aynesworth, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1895 May-August 7 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1895 August 14-23 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1895 October-December (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1896 January (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1896 February (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1896 March (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1896 April (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1896 May 7-25 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1896 May 27-July (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1896 September-1898 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1899-1901 September (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1901 November-1902 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1903 March-July 13 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1903 July 15-17 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1903 July 20-28 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1903 July 30-1914 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1921-1930 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1932 February (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1932 November-1933 March 15 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1933 March 17-28 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1934 August (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1935 February-November 5 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1935 November 6-17 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1935 November 18-December 4 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1935 December 5-13 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1935 December 14-1936 October (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1936 November 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1936 November 11-22 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1936 November 23-December 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth, 1936 December 3-9, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth (1 of 9), undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth (2 of 9), undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth (3 of 9), undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth (4 of 9), undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth (5 of 9), undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth (6 of 9), undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth (7 of 9), undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth (8 of 9), undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Maude Nancy Brian Aynesworth (9 of 9), undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - William T. Brian, Jr., 1931 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - William T. Brian, Jr., 1932 January-April (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - William T. Brian, Jr., 1932 September-1937, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Dottie Favrot, 1937-1939 April (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Dottie Favrot, 1939 July-1943 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Dottie Favrot, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Edna Gamble, 1923-1933 May 9 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Edna Gamble, 1933 May 22-1934 July 2 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Edna Gamble, 1934 October- 1935 July (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Edna Gamble, 1935 August-November 15 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Edna Gamble, 1935 November 29- 1936 January 29 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Edna Gamble, 1936 February 9-July (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Edna Gamble, 1936 August-October (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Edna Gamble, 1936 November- 1937 January (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Edna Gamble, 1937 February-May (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Edna Gamble, 1937 July-October (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Edna Gamble, 1937 November-1938 February (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Edna Gamble, 1938 March-July (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Edna Gamble, 1938 October-November 19 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Edna Gamble, 1938 November 22-December (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Edna Gamble, 1939 January-February 17 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Edna Gamble, 1939 February 28-November (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Edna Gamble, 1939 December-1940 September (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Edna Gamble, 1940 October-1941 March (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Edna Gamble, 1941 April-July 13 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Edna Gamble, 1941 July 31-December (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Edna Gamble, 1942-1943 January (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Edna Gamble, 1943 March-May (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Edna Gamble, 1943 June-1944 February (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Edna Gamble, 1944 October, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Edna Gamble, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Lucille Harrison, 1940-1943 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - J.E. Hickman, 1932-1941 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1930-1934 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1935 January-September 25 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1935 September 25-November (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1935 December-April 13 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1936 April 19-1937 August (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1937 September-1938 March 24 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1938 March 29-1939 August (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1939 September-1942 March (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1942 April-July (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1942 August-October (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1942 November-1943 March (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1943 April-June (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1943 July-August (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1943 September-1944 January 13 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Tom and Nancy Mann, 1944 January 31, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1931-1933 February 1 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1933 February 7-1934 November 15 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1934 December 4-1936 March 24 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1936 May 7-December 31 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1937 January-May (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1937 August-1938 April (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1938 September-October (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1938 November-1939 January 6 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1939 January 11-May 9 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1939 May 12-July 31 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1939 August-October (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1939 November-1940 February (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1940 March-July (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1940 August-1941 January (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1941 February 6-August 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1941 August 8-1942 February (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1942 March-September (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1942 October-1943 May (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1943 June-September (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1943 October-December (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Robert E. Milling, 1944, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Genealogical Materials, 1826-1949, undated; 2; This subseries consists of two document boxes and one oversized box.
    This subseries contains correspondence, family trees, and other materials pertaining to directly to the Aynesworths' genealogy. There is even a book by Ed Aynesworth entitled Aynesworth Genealogy found within this subseries. The materials are in average condition.
    The folders are organized alphabetically according to the type of material.
    - General, 1851-1925 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - General, 1931-1939, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Book: Aynesworth Genealogy: Ed M. Ainsworth, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1843-1906 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1908 February (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1908 March-April (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1909-1919 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1927-1937 October (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1937 December- 1938 February (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1938 March-1939 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1941-1949, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Family Trees, 1907-1908 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Family Trees, 1935-1941, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Family Trees (1 of 2), undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Family Trees (2 of 2), undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Records, 1826-1939 (Box 32 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - General, 1830-1965, undated; 3; This subseries contains two document boxes.
    This subseries contains subject files pertaining to various members of the Aynesworth family. Materials range from correspondence to literary productions. The materials are in average condition.
    The folders are organized alphabetically according to the names of Aynesworth's relatives.
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1934-1942 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1944-1961 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Brian Aynesworth, 1963-1965, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - C.I. Aynesworth, 1903-1905, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - G.L. Aynesworth, circa 1850s (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - G.L. Aynesworth, 1875-1892 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - G.L. Aynesworth, 1894-1897 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - G.L. Aynesworth, 1898-1903 April (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - G.L. Aynesworth, 1903 May-1906 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - G.L. Aynesworth, 1908-1913, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Joseph H. Aynesworth, 1931-1942 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Maude Brian Aynesworth, 1926-1937 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - M.B. Aynesworth: Gun Collection, 1947-1949 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Family: General: M.B. Aynesworth: Gun Collection, 1950-1958 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Family: General: M.B. Aynesworth: Gun Collection (1 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Family: General: M.B. Aynesworth: Gun Collection (2 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Family: General: M.B. Aynesworth: Literary Productions, 1934-1938 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Family: General: M.B. Aynesworth: Literary Productions, 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Family: General: M.B. Aynesworth: Literary Productions, 1949-1964 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Family: General: M.B. Aynesworth: Literary Productions, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Family: General: Mrs. S.E. Aynesworth, 1890-1907 (Box 7, Folder 16)